Guide to the Alan Sussmann Manne Papers
Stanford University. Libraries.
Department of Special Collections and University Archives
Alan Sussmann Manne papers
1957-2001
SC0794
Manne, Alan Sussmann
6 Linear feet (13 boxes)
The papers primarily pertain to Manne's research and writing on energy, energy policy, greenhouse gases, etc., and include correspondence, typescript papers, notes, figures, charts, and computer printouts, with some papers by others.
Department of Special Collections and University Archives Green Library 557 Escondido Mall Stanford, CA 94305-6064 Email: specialcollections@stanford.edu Phone: (650) 725-1022 URL: http://library.stanford.edu/spc
Administrative Information
Provenance
This collection was given to the Stanford University Archives by the estate of Alan Sussmann Manne in 2006.
Information about Access
The collection is open for research; materials must be requested at least 48 hours in advance of intended use.
Biographical/Historical Sketch
Alan S. Manne was on the faculty at Stanford University from 1961 until he retired in 1992, with the exception of two years teaching at Harvard (1974-1976). He was known for devising economic models pertaining to major world concerns and was the author of 128 papers and seven books.
Description of the Collection
The papers primarily pertain to Manne's research and writing on energy, energy policy, greenhouse gases, etc., and include correspondence, typescript papers, notes, figures, charts, and computer printouts, with some papers by others.
Access Terms
Manne, Alan Sussmann; Air--Pollution--Economic aspects; Energy policy.; Greenhouse effect, Atmospheric.
Collection Contents
- Göleborg, 1988 Oct (Box 1, Folder 1)
- Unequal Time Intervals, 1988-1989 (Box 1, Folder 2)
- Wheeler-NPCC, 1988 Aug (Box 1, Folder 3)
- Wheeler 1986 (Box 1, Folder 4)
- Random walk - Glynn, 1988 Jul (Box 1, Folder 5)
- CGE [computable general equilibrium] - India, 1988 (Box 1, Folder 6)
- Non-Commercial Energy (Box 1, Folder 7)
- India, 1988 (Box 1, Folder 8)
- Trinational, 1986 Feb (Box 1, Folder 9)
- Mexico Interdependence, 1986 (Box 1, Folder 10)
- Money - CGE, 1985 Dec (Box 1, Folder 11)
- Taiwan, 1985 Dec 2-6 (Box 1, Folder 12)
- GAMS [general algebraic modeling system] – MINOS [modular in-core nonlinear optimization system], CGE – AA [GCG with activity analysis], 1985 Nov (Box 1, Folder 13)
- Europe, Israel, 1985 spring (Box 1, Folder 14)
- Terms of Trade N,S, 1985 Apr (Box 1, Folder 15)
- Random walk - Taksar (Box 1, Folder 16)
- Trinational Energy, 1985 Feb (Box 1, Folder 17)
- Odell, 1984 Aug (Box 1, Folder 18)
- Eta - macro or a micro + CALCFG, 1984 Sep (Box 1, Folder 19)
- Mexico, 1984 Aug (Box 1, Folder 20)
- Octasolu, 1984 Jul (Box 1, Folder 21)
- China - CO2, 1984 May (Box 1, Folder 22)
- Pemex, 1984 Apr (Box 1, Folder 23)
- GTM, 1984 Feb (Box 1, Folder 24)
- Gas Trade Conferences, 1983-1984 (Box 1, Folder 25)
- OTM [oil trade model], 1983 (Box 1, Folder 26)
- Brussels, Vienna, Oxford, 1983 Nov (Box 1, Folder 27)
- IEW [International Energy Workshop] - UN - NY - 1983 Nov (Box 2, Folder 1)
- Gas - Mexico, 1983 Oct (Box 2, Folder 2)
- Canada, Israel, Europe, 1983 Apr-Jun (Box 2, Folder 3)
- Applied General Equilibrium, 1983 Jan (Box 2, Folder 4)
- Oil-gas Interfuel Subsitution, 1982-1983 (Box 2, Folder 5)
- Hung-po's eta - macro - Japan, etc., 1982 Dec (Box 2, Folder 6)
- Eta - macro - China, 1982 Nov (Box 2, Folder 7)
- Energy, Investments in, 1980-1982 Jul (Box 2, Folder 8)
- Mexico + IIASA, Israel, England, 1982 Jun (Box 2, Folder 9)
- China, Japan, 1982 Aug-Sep (Box 2, Folder 10)
- 2RT - Chenery Festschuft (Box 2, Folder 11)
- Bat Sheva, 1982 Jan (Box 2, Folder 12)
- Two-sector - IBRD, 1981 Dec (Box 2, Folder 13)
- Japan-China, 1981 Oct-Nov (Box 2, Folder 14)
- Israeli EMF [Energy Modeling Forum], 1981 (Box 2, Folder 15)
- Israel and Europe, 1981 Apr-Jun (Box 2, Folder 16)
- 3R - CEME documentation for Merrill, 1981 Jul (Box 2, Folder 17)
- TNFY - Richels, 1981 Apr-Sep (Box 2, Folder 18)
- 3R - IIASA - CEME - Hickman - 1980 Jul-1981 Jun (Box 2, Folder 19)
- Blitzer, 1980-1981 (Box 3, Folder 1)
- 9R corrected version, 1981 Mar (Box 3, Folder 2)
- EVMP, ch. 4 (Box 3, Folder 3)
- EVMP, ch. 9 (Box 3, Folder 4)
- EPRI [Electric Power Research Institute] - Plummer - Richels, 1980 Apr-Dec (Box 3, Folder 5)
- ETA - MACRO User's guide, 1978-1980 (Box 3, Folder 6)
- Mexico, Calgary, 1980 Aug 30-Sep 12 (Box 3, Folder 7)
- Europe, 1980 Jun-Jul (Box 3, Folder 8)
- Health and eno - EMF (Box 3, Folder 9)
- Public Discount Rate (Box 3, Folder 10)
- MCW [Manne Chao Wilson] algorithm, 1977-1979 (Box 3, Folder 11)
- Miami, 1978 (Box 3, Folder 12)
- Trip to Europe, 1979 Sep-Oct (Box 3, Folder 13)
- 1980 Overview: Revise base - yer data 9/79 (Box 3, Folder 14)
- Prob Assessments, Dec Analysis, Manne and Richels, 1979 Jan (Box 3, Folder 15)
- Dantzig: Memoirs About My Own Contributions To Linear Programming and Extensions; Some Reminiscence and a Review of My Research, 1976 Jan (Box 3, Folder 16)
- GE [General Electric] - Vermilyea, UK (Box 3, Folder 17)
- NASA P-Aspen (Box 3, Folder 18)
- MEPA [Model for Energy Policy Analysis] (Box 3, Folder 19)
- Commercialization of Inexhaustible Energy Resources: A Simulator for a Pocket Calculator; Manne, 1978 Feb 1 (Box 3, Folder 20)
- Pakistan, 1978 Oct (Box 4, Folder 1)
- DRI – Oil Refg (Box 4, Folder 2)
- OPEC (Box 4, Folder 3)
- L. Hamilton – joint paper, 1977 May (Box 4, Folder 4)
- E-R Model, 1977 (Box 4, Folder 5)
- 70 quad memo, 1977 Jun (Box 4, Folder 6)
- CONAES [Comm. on Nuclear and Alternative Energy Sources] Overview Committee Round #2 responses, 1977 Jan (Box 4, Folder 7)
- CONAES memos to/from Tjalling Koopmans (Box 4, Folder 8)
- Returned questionnaires (round 2) + code sheet (Box 4, Folder 9)
- List of round 2 responses (Box 4, Folder 10)
- ETA - 7 Ben Daniel, 1976 Jun (Box 4, Folder 11)
- Ford - Nuclear Policy, 1976 (Box 4, Folder 12)
- Nuclear safety - LHS, 1975 Mar (Box 4, Folder 13)
- ANS [American Nuclear Society], Toronto, 1976 Jun (Box 4, Folder 14)
- Sacramento Testimony, 1976 Feb (Box 4, Folder 15)
- Council on For Rel, 1976 Mar (Box 4, Folder 16)
- Jackson Campaign (Box 4, Folder 17)
- Commissioners of Public Utilities Control Authority (Box 4, Folder 18)
- Energy Seminar in Rehovoth (Box 4, Folder 19)
- Pu Island [nuclear fuel issues] (Box 4, Folder 20)
- Institute for Energy Studies - Oak Ridge (Box 4, Folder 21)
- Moratorium, 1975 Sep-1976 Jan (Box 4, Folder 22)
- RAND - WASH1535, 1975 May-Jun (Box 5, Folder 1)
- Bergendahl - Pressman, Koopmans notes on elasticities and Bergendahl on Pressman (Box 5, Folder 2)
- Preliminary memo to Alessis (Box 5, Folder 3)
- IIASA Energy Memos (Box 5, Folder 4)
- Waiting for Breeder, 1974 Apr (Box 5, Folder 5)
- EDF - IIASA, 1974 (Box 5, Folder 6)
- Energy Modeling Seminar, 1973 Jul 23-27 (Box 5, Folder 7)
- Stanford Files (syllabi, faculty reports), 1966-1973 (Box 5, Folder 8)
- 74-1 Blizer and Manne - Employment (Box 5, Folder 9)
- Doomsday Models IRI talk, 1973 Jun (Box 5, Folder 10)
- Truncation Problem (Box 5, Folder 11)
- India, Econ 192, 1971-1972 (Box 5, Folder 12)
- TN’s calculations of Ω (t) (Box 5, Folder 13)
- On the Role of Machinery Production in the Economic Development of Mexico. Alan S. Manne. (Box 5, Folder 14)
- Conversion Factors (Box 5, Folder 15)
- Chenery Memorandum - Feb 1957 "Capital-labor Substitution in Metalworking Processes", 1957 Feb (Box 5, Folder 16)
- Machine tool prices (Box 5, Folder 17)
- Miscellaneous models, pre 1966 (Box 5, Folder 18)
- Mercado de Valores, 1963, 1965 (Box 5, Folder 19)
- Carbon Emissions and Petroleum Resources, 2001 Jun (Box 5, Folder 20)
- Bush paper (George Bush School of Government and Public Service, Texas A&M University) "Energy, the environment and the economy: hedging our bets", 2001 Apr (Box 5, Folder 21)
- Shock (Measuring an Economic Shock), 2001 Feb (Box 5, Folder 22)
- Snowmass, 2000 Aug (Box 5, Folder 23)
- ETA [energy technology assessment] in MERGE, EMF 19, 2000 Mar (Box 5, Folder 24)
- Rudra, Ashok – correspondence, 1973 (Box 5, Folder 25)
- EIS Paris, 1999 Jun (Box 6, Folder 1)
- MERGE [Model for Evaluating Regional and Global Effects on greenhouse gas reduction policies] (Box 6, Folder 2)
- EMF14 - Uncertainty. Rome, 1998 Oct (Box 6, Folder 3)
- Rome, 1999 Oct (Box 6, Folder 4)
- Rome, 1998 Oct (Box 6, Folder 5)
- ACCF [American Council for Capital Formation], 1998 Sep (Box 6, Folder 6)
- Aero - Snowmass, 1997 (Box 6, Folder 7)
- ROR - Gunter Stephon, 1998 Feb (Box 6, Folder 8)
- SIUC, 1996 Nov (Box 6, Folder 9)
- Discounting, 96 Nov (Box 6, Folder 10)
- Hedging - Uncertainty subgroup, 1996 Apr (Box 6, Folder 11)
- Altruism, 1996 Mar-Apr (Box 6, Folder 12)
- ETSAP, 1995 May (Box 6, Folder 13)
- Boulder, 1995 Apr (Box 6, Folder 14)
- JMU [Joint Maximization under Uncertainty] – Olsen, 1994 Nov (Box 6, Folder 15)
- Markal-Macro/Trade, 1994 (Box 6, Folder 16)
- IEW – HNL, 1994 Jun (Box 6, Folder 17)
- EMF14, 1994 Jun (Box 6, Folder 18)
- B/B trans, 1994 May-Apr (Box 6, Folder 19)
- Mkt shares – BN, 1993-1994 (Box 6, Folder 20)
- Pareto – optimal IA, 1993 Dec (Box 6, Folder 21)
- Time pref – Schelling, 1994 (Box 6, Folder 22)
- Greenhouse Gas Abatement, 1994 Nov (Box 7, Folder 1)
- The Deacon's Masterpiece or, the Wonderful "One-Hoss Shay," Oliver Wendell Holmes (Box 7, Folder 2)
- Miscellaneous (Box 7, Folder 3)
- Agricultural Development Corporation (Box 7, Folder 4)
- Reprints (Box 7, Folder 58)
- A Re-Examination of the Acceleration Principle (Box 8, Folder 1)
- Reprints (Box 8, Folder 25)
- Reprints (Box 9, Folder 16)
- Reprints (Box 10, Folder 13)
- Appendix to Manne/Chao/Wilson paper (Box 10, Folder 4)
- Memo 71-2 – Inman – User’s Guide IPE (Box 10, Folder 5)
- Operations Research 247/237 – Manne 9219 – Reprints (Box 10, Folder 68)
- Reprints (Box 11, Folder 16)
- Reprints (Box 12, Folder 14)
- ICE – MIT Press (Box 12, Folder 5)
- P.A. Monograph – Wiley (Box 12, Folder 6)
- Book reviews and Miscellaneous (Box 12, Folder 7)
- CGE for IA (Box 12, Folder 8)
- Manne, "GAMS/MINOS: Three Examples,", 1986 Dec (Box 13, Folder 1)
- Operations Research 347 class materials (syllabi, homework, handouts, lecture notes), 1981-1992 (Box 13, Folder 2)
- "Comparison of solution algorithms for applied equilibrium problems," paper with no author or date given (Box 13, Folder 3)
- "Personal Editor II: Learning and Reference" - computer program manual for a DOS system (Box 13, Folder 4)
- GAMS - The Solver Manuals, 1993 (Box 13, Folder 5)
- GAMS - Installation and System Notes, 1995 (Box 13, Folder 6)
- MINOS 5.4 User's Guide (preliminary) by Bruce A. Murtagh and Michael A. Saunders. Technical Report SOL 83-20R, 1993 Mar (Box 13, Folder 7)